{"data":[{"question":"European football is played in 80 countries, _________ it the most popular sport in the world.","a":"makes","b":"making","c":"to make","d":"made","answer":"2","explain":"\n- When a participle phrase concludes a main clause and modifies a word farther up in the sentence, you will need a comma. The pattern looks like this: main clause + , + participle phrase. ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"6","type":"1"},{"question":"___ from such heavy pollution already, it may now be too late to clean up the river.","a":"Suffering","b":"Having suffered","c":"Suffered","d":"To suffer","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Present perfect tense \n-Having suffered from such heavy pollution already= participle phrase describing the noun \"it\" ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"6","type":"1"},{"question":"As I joined the carnival with my friends, I got ___ from them.","a":"spared","b":"lost","c":"missed","d":"separated","answer":"4","explain":"\n- Get + past participle = be + past participle \n- To make passive structures in informal spoken English, we sometime use get instead of be with the past participle","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"6","type":"1"},{"question":"___ some officials, the president inspected the army.","a":"Followed by","b":"Followed","c":"Having been followed by","d":"Being followed","answer":"1","explain":"\n- When a participle phrase introduces a main clause, separate the two sentence components with a comma. The pattern looks like this: participle phrase + , + main clause. \n- A present participle attributes a quality of action to the noun, which is viewed as undertaking the action \n- A past participle views the noun as having undergone the action expressed by the participle ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"6","type":"1"},{"question":"___ more attention, pets could have grown better.","a":"To give","b":"Given","c":"Having given","d":"Giving","answer":"2","explain":"\n- When a participle phrase introduces a main clause, separate the two sentence components with a comma. The pattern looks like this: participle phrase + , + main clause. \n- A present participle attributes a quality of action to the noun, which is viewed as undertaking the action \n- A past participle views the noun as having undergone the action expressed by the participle","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"6","type":"1"},{"question":"___ in thought, the man almost ran into the car in front of him.","a":"Having lost","b":"Losing","c":"To lose","d":"Lost","answer":"4","explain":"\n- When a participle phrase introduces a main clause, separate the two sentence components with a comma. The pattern looks like this: participle phrase + , + main clause. \n- A present participle attributes a quality of action to the noun, which is viewed as undertaking the action \n- A past participle views the noun as having undergone the action expressed by the participle ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"6","type":"1"},{"question":"What's the language ___ in Holland?","a":"spoken","b":"speaking","c":"to speak","d":"be spoken","answer":"1","explain":"\n- When a participle phrase concludes a main clause and is describing the word right in front of it, you need no punctuation to connect the two sentence parts. The pattern looks like this: main clause + participle phrase \n- A present participle attributes a quality of action to the noun, which is viewed as undertaking the action \n- A past participle views the noun as having undergone the action expressed by the participle","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"6","type":"1"},{"question":"Most of the guests ___ to the wedding were famous politicians.","a":"to invite","b":"invited","c":"inviting","d":"being invited","answer":"2","explain":"\n- When a participle phrase concludes a main clause and is describing the word right in front of it, you need no punctuation to connect the two sentence parts. The pattern looks like this: main clause + participle phrase \n- A present participle attributes a quality of action to the noun, which is viewed as undertaking the action \n- A past participle views the noun as having undergone the action expressed by the participle ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"6","type":"1"},{"question":"The first textbooks ___ for teaching English as a foreign language came out in the 16th century.","a":"to be written","b":"having written","c":"written","d":"being written","answer":"3","explain":"\n- When a participle phrase concludes a main clause and is describing the word right in front of it, you need no punctuation to connect the two sentence parts. The pattern looks like this: main clause + participle phrase \n- A present participle attributes a quality of action to the noun, which is viewed as undertaking the action \n- A past participle views the noun as having undergone the action expressed by the participle","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"6","type":"1"},{"question":"The Olympic Games, ___ in 776 B.C., did not include women players.","a":"to be first played","b":"first played","c":"to be first playing","d":"first playing","answer":"2","explain":"\n- When a participle phrase introduces a main clause, separate the two sentence components with a comma. The pattern looks like this:participle phrase + , + main clause","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"6","type":"1"}]}